<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Will Carcamo</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Will Carcamo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Special ggplot2 Variables</title>
      <link>/2019/06/25/special-ggplot2-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/25/special-ggplot2-variables/</guid>
      <description>Data Visualization in R &amp;amp; LabelsI often treat building data visualizations in R as a fun puzzle. Prior to learning how to use ggplot2, I would do all of my graphs in excel. Making eye catching graphs in excel is often easier and quicker (especially if you follow Stephanie Evergreen). One feature that I really enjoy in excel is the ease of adding/removing data point labels and re-positioning them with a mouse to get them exactly where I want them, but excel is a tool designed by others for general use and has its own limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Python: Part 2</title>
      <link>/2019/06/17/learning-python-2rmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/17/learning-python-2rmd/</guid>
      <description>Learning PythonThis post is a continuation of a learning python. In this post, I will extend the last post and focus on tidyverse equivalents to:
Mutate columnsSummarize data (Groupby)Pipe functions (%&amp;gt;%)Setting up Python in RmarkdownLoad Modules and Dataimport pandas as pdimport numpy as npurl = &amp;#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday/master/data/2019/2019-05-28/winemag-data-130k-v2.csv&amp;#39;dat = pd.read_csv(url, index_col=0)Settings for better outputThis blog is built through the blogdown package and uses Rmarkdown files that render to HTML documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Python: The Beginning</title>
      <link>/2019/05/31/learning-python-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/31/learning-python-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>Learning PythonI often see a debate online between Python and R as programming languages for Data Science. I am not interested in continuing that debate here, but rather just want to continue to learn other programming languages and have another tool available to use. I often read online Python is better for general use programming while R was developed with statisticians in mind. If that is the case I think it would be helpful to start learning Python and see where I can use it for my advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday - MyAnimeList</title>
      <link>/2019/04/23/tidy-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/23/tidy-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>MyAnimelist.netThis week TidyTuesday posted data from an anime and manga social networking and social cataloging website, MyAnimeList (MAL). This data will be interesting to examine because last summer I started watching anime shows and got hooked. I am a little embarrassed to admit it but I’ve seen a lot of different shows since then. I hope I get to find some new shows that I can watch later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outline a Route on a Map</title>
      <link>/2019/04/21/google-map-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/21/google-map-api/</guid>
      <description>Working with MapsIf you are interesting in learning about how to use R to work with geospatial data, I would first point you in the direction of reading Geocomputation in R. I previously thought that you had to use special software like ArcGIS in order to make maps but I found it not too difficult using certain R packages to make simple maps quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First #TidyTuesday</title>
      <link>/2019/04/02/tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/02/tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>Joining #TidyTuesdayEvery Tuesday, I often see submissions from the #rstats community on twitter about their #TidyTuesday projects. #TidyTuesdays are weekly data projects posted online by the R4DS (R for Data Science) community for anyone interested in working on developing their skills wrangling data within the R ecosystem. Feel free to check out the #tidytuesday repository on github for more information.
I felt it would be only natural for my first post to be joining this community and moving from being an observer to a participant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description> Loading&amp;hellip; 
 First Name  Last Name  E-Mail  City  State AL CA IL      Send   -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>.leaflet {margin: auto;}A New HobbyMy name is Will. I am not much of a programmer, but I am working on it. The first programming language I learned was R. I am trying to explore what I am capable of building with R and this site is one example of what someone can do. For me, this site is simply a place for me to track what I learn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>