<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ggplot2 on Will Carcamo</title>
    <link>/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ggplot2 on Will Carcamo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Special ggplot2 Variables</title>
      <link>/2019/06/25/special-ggplot2-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/25/special-ggplot2-variables/</guid>
      <description>Data Visualization in R &amp;amp; LabelsI often treat building data visualizations in R as a fun puzzle. Prior to learning how to use ggplot2, I would do all of my graphs in excel. Making eye catching graphs in excel is often easier and quicker (especially if you follow Stephanie Evergreen). One feature that I really enjoy in excel is the ease of adding/removing data point labels and re-positioning them with a mouse to get them exactly where I want them, but excel is a tool designed by others for general use and has its own limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday - MyAnimeList</title>
      <link>/2019/04/23/tidy-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/23/tidy-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>MyAnimelist.netThis week TidyTuesday posted data from an anime and manga social networking and social cataloging website, MyAnimeList (MAL). This data will be interesting to examine because last summer I started watching anime shows and got hooked. I am a little embarrassed to admit it but I’ve seen a lot of different shows since then. I hope I get to find some new shows that I can watch later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First #TidyTuesday</title>
      <link>/2019/04/02/tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/02/tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>Joining #TidyTuesdayEvery Tuesday, I often see submissions from the #rstats community on twitter about their #TidyTuesday projects. #TidyTuesdays are weekly data projects posted online by the R4DS (R for Data Science) community for anyone interested in working on developing their skills wrangling data within the R ecosystem. Feel free to check out the #tidytuesday repository on github for more information.
I felt it would be only natural for my first post to be joining this community and moving from being an observer to a participant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>